Matt Prestlien

+1 (360) 303-6901 me@mattprestlien.com http://mattprestlien.com/

Denver, CO 80223

Profile

Professional and versatile engineer with a penchant for user-focused design hailing from veteran SaaS firms. Experience and acute interest in web app engineering and design, specifically with React/Angular and hybrid frameworks for mobile. Maintain an intermediate knowledge in backend technologies such as C# and Go. Work proficiently alone and adeptly within group or team dynamics, coupled with excellent time management skills and attention to detail.

Experience

Fullstack Software Engineer, Reserve Trust; Littleton, CO - Nov 2019 - Present

Brought on as one of the first hires to an early-stage fintech startup, within weeks produced a React dashboard MVP for analysis of transactional data based on high-fidelity mockups. Worked with senior staff to produce a prototype cryptographically signed, event-sourced and idempotent wire transfer API in NodeJS. Pivoted quickly and learned Go in order to create a production-ready API with an enterprise security model, highlighted by best-in-class developer experience delivered via Docker. Readily assisted with IT infrastructure and digitalization of existing onboarding workflow.

Frontend Software Developer, SCRAM Systems; Littleton, CO - Mar 2018 - Nov 2019

Tasked with building an offender-facing application for parole management, suggested Ionic for accelerated mobile development against <u>ASP.net</u> Core webAPIs and Azure Functions on the backend. Architected a strong Angular application using TypeScript and RxJS + NgRx. Built out CI pipelines for the app. Added unit testing and UI testing using Jest and BrowserStack. Implemented Auth0 for an authentication solution. Hired and trained a junior developer. Troubleshot both native issues for iOS/Android and problems with Azure. Explored aspects of domain-driven and event-driven systems. Worked with UI/UX team to improve design-dev workflow and created a frontend focused group within the org to share knowledge.

Cordova Engineer, SpiderOak; Kansas City, MO (Remote) - Dec 2016 - Mar 2018

Focused on building an end-to-end encrypted enterprise chat application. Cordova expertise applied to quickly and efficiently solve performance/UX issues and implement features with advanced CSS tactics. Helped the team to create a React/Redux mobile app while maintaining an organized codebase responsive enough to use on the desktop via Electron.

Software Engineer, ServiceMonster; Bellingham, WA - Dec 2014 - Dec 2016

Education

Associate in Liberal Studies, Whatcom Community College; Bellingham, WA - 2012-2015

Skills

Languages and Frameworks

Mature problem-solving skills and engineering process. Worked extensively in Javascript, C# and Golang. Experience with Swift and Java, primarily within the context of mobile front-ends and their RESTful web services. Demonstrable deep understanding of single-state application flow via state management frameworks paradigm coupled with more recent learnings around Go and ASP.net. Communication

Work methodically with a team of individuals in order to achieve a common goal while keeping stakeholder input paramount. Adept with peer review, refactoring and latest standards to ensure development projects are well-maintained. Implementations have been praised by peers for their accuracy to mockups while ensuring strong code hygiene.

Technologies

- Angular/React
- Ionic/MaterialUI/Sass
- ES6+/Typescript
- Capacitor/Electron
- iOS/Android SDKs
- Go/gin-gonic
- C#/ASP.net Core
 - REST/Event Sourcing
- Swagger/OpenAPI
 - OAuth 2.0 Flows
- Docker
- CI/CD
- JIRA/AzDO
- GCP/Azure
 - Sketch/Figma